Guide to the Theatre Authority Records WAG.183
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Theatre Authority Records
1897-2000
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Theatre Authority
Roberts, Beverly
Greenspan, John
Hoffman, Harold
WAG.183
8.75 Linear Feet in 14 manuscript boxes, 2 flat boxes, and 3 folders in oversized shared box.
The Theatre Authority Records (1897-2000) is made up of files from the Theatre Authority and materials created by Beverly Roberts, a former Theatre Authority president, and her family. The Theatre Authority, founded in 1934, provides clearances for members of the unions of the 4As (Associated Actors and Artistes of America) to participate in fundraisers (such as benefits or telethons).
Scope and Content Note
The Theatre Authority Records (1897-2000) is made up of files from the Theatre Authority and materials created by Beverly Roberts and her family. The Theatre Authority files mostly include event clearances and governance materials, as well as material produced by their representative organizations--the American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, American Guild of Musical Artists, American Guild of Variety Artists, Actors' Equity Association, and the Screen Actors Guild.
The collection also contains materials related to Beverly Roberts, a former president of the Theatre Authority, and her family. These materials consist of playbills, family photographs, manuscripts written by her father Arthur Knapp Roberts, and materials related to Roberts' career as an actress.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Beverly Roberts, former Theatre Authority President, via Harold Hoffman in 1985. The accession number associated with this gift is 1950.288
Another donation was made by John Greenspan, Theatre Authority Treasurer, in 2001. The accession number associated with this gift is 1984.003.
Historical Note
The Theatre Authority was founded in 1934 as "...a non-profit regulatory organization representing the professional actors' unions, charitable actors' guilds and others. It is the clearinghouse for all benefits, telethons and fund-raising events which wish to use the talents of professional performers" (Memo from Theatre Authority, "A Sponsor's Guide, 1981). The Authority grew out of a concern on the part of several stars over the legitimacy and financial respectability of organizations that requested their services.
The Theatre Authority provides clearances for members of the unions of the 4As (Associated Actors and Artistes of America) to participate in fundraisers (such as benefits or telethons). The organization determines if the beneficiaries are legitimate, regulates scheduling, and monitors unfair demands on union members during fundraisers.
The Executive Committee consisted of representatives from the American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, American Guild of Musical Artists, American Guild of Variety Artists, Actors' Equity Association, and the Screen Actors Guild. In the 2000s, administration of the organization was taken over by Actors' Equity. Prior to 2014, Theatre Authority had two offices: Theatre Authority West administered clearances West of Omaha, Nebraska and Theatre Authority, Inc. administered East of Omaha.
Other organizations represented on the Board of Directors were the Actors Fund of America, Authors League Fund, Catholic Actors Guild, League of New York Theatres and Producers, and the Negro Actors Guild.
Presidents of the Theatre Authority include: Conrad Nagel (founder, 1934-?), Sidney Blackmere, Ed Sullivan, Paul Dulizell (1942-1960), Beverly Roberts (1954-1977), Harold Hoffman (1977-?).
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series:
Series I: Theatre Authority Files
Series II: Beverly Roberts Family Materials
Related Materials
Actors' Equity Association Records (WAG 011)
American Guild of Variety Artists Records (WAG 95)
Actors' Fund Records (WAG 36)
Associated Actors and Artistes of America Records (WAG 110)
Fundraising.; Theater -- United States; Actors -- United States; Roberts, Beverly; Greenspan, John; Hoffman, Harold; Actors' Equity Association; American Federation of Television and Radio Artists; American Guild of Musical Artists; American Guild of Variety Artists; Screen Actors Guild; Associated Actors and Artistes of America
- Series I: Theatre Authority Files, 1938-2000; 7.5 Linear Feet in 11 manuscript boxes, 2 oversized flat boxes, and 3 folders in oversized shared box.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by file title.
  Scope and Contents
  This series is made up of files from the Theatre Authority offices, including governance materials, meeting minutes, clearance reports, the Monthly Review (their newsletter), financial reports, correspondence, legal proceedings, event planning materials, clippings, files on charitable organizations, as well as material produced by their representative organizations--the American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (AFTRA), American Guild of Musical Artists (AGMA), American Guild of Variety Artists (AGVA), Actors' Equity Association, and the Screen Actors Guild. Much of the materials focus on the organization's efforts to recruit celebrities to their Advisory Committee as well as the National Labor Relations Board lawsuit with the Children's Miracle Network.
  - Actors Fund of America, 1980-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - Actors' Equity Association (British), 1967-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Actors' Equity Association (Canadian), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Actors' Equity Association (NYC), 1957-2000 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Actors' Equity Association (Regional Offices), 1979-1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Actors' Work Program, circa 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Advisory Committee, 1968-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - AFTRA Code of Fair Practice, 1973-1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - AFTRA National, 1957-2000 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - AFTRA Regional Offices, 1978-1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - AFTRA Rule 15, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - AFTRA--History of Show Biz Unions, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - AGMA, 1964-1999 (Box 2, Folder 10, Box 3, Folder 1)
  - AGVA National, 1979-1999 (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
  - AGVA Regional, 1954-1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - AGVA--Theatre Authority Funds for Benefit, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - AIDS Organizations (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - American Theatre Wing, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - An Evening of Stars--United Negro College Fund Benefit, 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 9-11)
  - Arthritis Foundation Correspondence, 1977-1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bureau of the Census, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Certificate of Report of Existence, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Charities Registration, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Chase Bank, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Children's Miracle Network Lawsuit, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 6-12)
  - Clippings Scrapbooks, 1935-1939 (Box 12, Box 13)
  - Cost of Living, 1982-2000 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Davis, Jr., Sammy, 1956-1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Dick Moore and Associates, 1976-1999 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Directors Guild of America, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dramatists Guild Fund, 1955-1999 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Episcopal Actors Guild, 1954-1999 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Fact Finding Committee, 1967-1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Falana, Lola, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Farm Aid Benefit, 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Fiscal Policies, 1959-1971 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - George Heller Memorial Foundation, 1957-1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Harry Van Arsdale, Jr. Labor History Project, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Historic News Items, 1981-1991 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - History, 1953-1985 (Box 5, Folder 13-15, Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Homer, Lawrence, 1996-2000 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Ira Wheeler Proposal, 1962-1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - League of American Theatres and Producers, 1954-1999 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Letterhead, 1976-1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - McDermott, Will and Emery, 1989-1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Motion Picture Players Welfare Fund, 1991-2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Nagel, Conrad, 1960-1970 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - National Charities Information Bureau, 1978-2000 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - National Executive Service Corps Project, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - National Labor Relations Board, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 11, Box 7, Folder 1)
  - New York City Central Labor Council, 1978-1983 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - New York State Legislature (Laws re Charitable Fundraising), 1954 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1938-1975 (Box 7, Folder 4-8)
  - Past Officers, 1954-1987 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Performers' Rates Schedules, 1973-1978 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Policy Guides, 1952-1988 (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
  - Political Events Policy, 1959-1990 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Portrait, undated (Box Shared Tamiment OS005, Folder 3)
  - Powell, Jane, 1993-1996 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Report to Executive Committee, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Resolution by Unions in Support of Theatre Authority, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Responses to Tony Roberts' Letter to Performers, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, 1984-1989 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Roberts, Tony, 1998-2000 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Sam A. Scribner Resolution, 1941 (Box Shared Tamiment OS005, Folder 14)
  - Screen Actors Guild, 1956-2000 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Screen Actors Guild (California), 1999 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Tax Information, 1932-1997 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Theatre Authority Brochures, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 8-9)
  - Theatre Authority Brochures--revision, 1981-1989, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 10-11, Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Theatre Authority West, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Theatre Authority West By-Laws, 1960-1997 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Theatre Authority West Correspondence, 1997-2000 (Box 9, Folder 4-9, Box 10, Folder 1-3)
  - Theatre Authority West Events, 1978-1995 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Theatre Authority West Financial Information, 1959-1976 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Theatre Authority West Incorporation and By-Laws, 1981-1987 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Theatre Authority West Minutes, 1994-2000 (Box 10, Folder 7, Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Theatre Authority West Pension Plan, 1979-1982 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Theatre Development Fund, 1981-1999 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Theatre for America, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Theatre Guild, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Theatre League Alliance Ovation Awards, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Theatre League Alliance--Karen Rushfield, 1989-1991 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Theatre Owners, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Theatrical Index, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Theatrical Mutual Association, 1982-1985 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Tissue Banks International, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - United Cerebral Palsy Telethon, 1988 (Box Shared Tamiment OS005, Folder 15)
  - United States Treasury Exempt Certificates, 1942-1985 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Will Rogers Memorial Fund, 1964-1981 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Series II: Beverly Roberts Family Materials, 1897-1962; 1.25 Linear Feet in two manuscript boxes and one half manuscript box.
  Beverly Roberts Family Materials series contains mostly materials created by Beverly Roberts and her father, Arthur Knapp Roberts. The series includes two copies of Arthur Knapp Roberts' manuscript entitled "Read It and Weep" as well as press materials from his performances. It also documents some of Beverly Roberts' career as an actress including playbills, newspaper clippings, and fan club publications. There are also some clippings, programs, and correspondence related to Justine Roberts as an impersonator and Alonso Foster's performances. The series also includes family photographs, most of which are unlabelled, that include headshots, photographs from travel and around Southern California, and other portraits of family members and pets.
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Beverly Book, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Beverly Roberts Fan Club, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Beverly Roberts Photographs, 1910s-1940s (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Elaine Dickson and Arthur K. Roberts, 1940-1976 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Family Photographs, 1897-1944 (Box 14, Folder 5-12)
  - Filmland Fan Club 30th Anniversary Book, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Photo Album, early 1900s (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Playbills, 1942-1945 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Press Notices, 1907-1925 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - "Read It and Weep" Contracts, circa 1961 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - "Read It and Weep" Manuscripts, circa 1961 (Box 15, Folder 5-8, Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Travel Journal, 1935 (Box 16, Folder 3)